<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[danielabaron.me RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Insights and experiences from Daniela Baron, a software engineer sharing problem-solving techniques, learning strategies, and career development.]]></description><link>https://danielabaron.me</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 12:37:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Re-imagining Technical Interviews: Valuing Experience Over Exam Skills]]></title><description><![CDATA[Exploring the shortcomings of traditional technical interviews and advocating for more relevant assessment methods to better reflect the demands of modern software engineering roles.]]></description><link>https://danielabaron.me/blog/reimagining-technical-interviews/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danielabaron.me/blog/reimagining-technical-interviews/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>As I navigate the job search process anew, I&apos;m struck by how sub-optimal technical interviewing has become. This post will review the…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Build a Rails App with Slack Part 5: Slash Command With Block Kit Response]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn how to build a Slack application with Rails in this comprehensive multi-part series. Part 5 covers receiving a slash command and responding with a visually appealing block kit UI response.]]></description><link>https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-slack-app-part5-slash-block-kit-response/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-slack-app-part5-slash-block-kit-response/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Welcome to the fifth installment of this multi-part series on building a Slack application with Rails. This series will guide you through…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Build a Rails App with Slack Part 4: Receive Modal Submission]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn how to build a Slack application with Rails in this comprehensive multi-part series. Part 4 covers handling a modal submission action, saving the feedback to the database, and replying to the user with a private DM confirming their submission.]]></description><link>https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-slack-app-part4-action-modal-submission/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-slack-app-part4-action-modal-submission/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Welcome to the fourth installment of this multi-part series on building a Slack application with Rails. This series will guide you through…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Build a Rails App with Slack Part 3: Slash Command with Modal Response]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn how to build a Slack application with Rails in this comprehensive multi-part series. Part 3 covers configuring and handling a Slack Slash Command to perform a business action and responding with a modal form response in the channel.]]></description><link>https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-slack-app-part3-slash-command-with-modal-response/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-slack-app-part3-slash-command-with-modal-response/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Welcome to the third installment of this multi-part series on building a Slack application with Rails. This series will guide you through…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Build a Rails App with Slack Part 2: Slash Command with Text Response]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn how to build a Slack application with Rails in this comprehensive multi-part series. Part 2 covers configuring and handling a Slack Slash Command to perform a business action and responding with a markdown text response in the channel.]]></description><link>https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-slack-app-part2-slash-command-with-text-response/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-slack-app-part2-slash-command-with-text-response/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Welcome to the second installment of this multi-part series on building a Slack application with Rails. This series will guide you through…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Build a Rails App with Slack Part 1: OAuth]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn how to build a Slack application with Rails in this comprehensive multi-part series. Part 1 covers setting up a new Rails app, configuring OAuth for authentication, and laying the foundation for Retro Pulse, an app designed to enhance agile retrospectives on Slack. Follow along for step-by-step instructions and valuable insights into integrating Slack with Ruby on Rails.]]></description><link>https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-slack-app-part1-oauth/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-slack-app-part1-oauth/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Welcome to the first installment of this multi-part series on building a Slack application with Rails. This series will guide you through…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Some Elegance with Rails Caching]]></title><description><![CDATA[Explore the elegance of Rails caching using the 'fetch' method to optimize performance and easily handle slow operations.]]></description><link>https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-cache-elegance/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-cache-elegance/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>I was recently reviewing a pull request (PR) for a Rails project that was introducing Rails caching. Specifically, low-level caching for…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[VSCode Markdown Basics: Customize Fenced Code Block Choices]]></title><description><![CDATA[Customize the fenced code block snippet in VSCode to include additional languages for a more efficient markdown writing experience in engineering docs and blog posts.]]></description><link>https://danielabaron.me/blog/vscode-markdown-basics-custom-fenced-languages/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danielabaron.me/blog/vscode-markdown-basics-custom-fenced-languages/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>VSCode is a great editor for authoring markdown documents. I use it frequently for writing engineering documentation and blog posts. VSCode…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Optimized Model Auditing with PaperTrail]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn how to optimize model auditing in your Rails application using the PaperTrail gem by setting up separate audit tables for each model, enhancing performance and organization in the auditing process]]></description><link>https://danielabaron.me/blog/model-audit-paper-trail/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danielabaron.me/blog/model-audit-paper-trail/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Model auditing plays an important role in tracking changes within a Rails application. While several gems are available to implement this…</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Efficient Database Queries in Rails: A Practical Approach]]></title><description><![CDATA[Explore a practical guide to optimizing database queries in Rails applications. Learn step-by-step enhancements, from indexing strategies to column selection.]]></description><link>https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-query-perf/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://danielabaron.me/blog/rails-query-perf/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>This post will walk through a step-by-step approach to PostgreSQL query enhancement in Rails applications. From indexing strategies to…</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>